I will take this my message from the Book of John 15, verse 11.
John 15, verse 11.
Are you there?
“I have told you this so that my joy may be in you and that your joy may be complete.”
It means without God’s joy, we don’t have joy.
So, what is not done right is not done at all.
When something is not complete, it is nothing.
It is not right.
The joy of God makes our joy what?
(Complete.)
... makes our joy complete.
This is what the Bible says here.
“I have told you this so that my joy may be in you and that your joy may be complete.”
(Amen.)
Think about that.
So, it means without God’s joy, we have no joy.
What is not done well is not done at all.
Don't forget the Book of John 16:33.
“These things I speak to you, in Me, you may have peace.”
(Amen.)
And this John 15:11 - it is telling us that without God's joy, we have no joy.
This means peace is synonymous to joy.
Peace is synonymous - that is, another word for peace is joy.
It is a fruit of faith – joy!
It is a fruit of what?
It is a fruit - like a mango on a tree.
You have a fruit on the top - the tree is faith.
Mango on top of... - joy, peace, love.
It is a fruit of faith.
It is a fruit that comes from the recreated spirit – love, peace, joy.
It means, without faith, no joy.
Faith is the tree that carries that.
This is why joy is something that only believers have; no other people.
If you are not a believer, you are without joy.
Joy is something that only believers have.
Tell your neighbour: "If you are not a believer, you have no joy."
If you are not a believer, you have no joy.
It’s not something you can manufacture or create by yourself.
You think, "I need joy, I need joy."
Money - millions of dollars cannot give you that joy.
The world may have happiness – they find that in their environment and in their surroundings.
The world, those who are not believers - they may have happiness.
Happiness, when they give you a million dollars you say, "Oh! Happiness has come!"
You begin to say, "Hey!" But not joy!
One day you receive a phone call from the president,
"Hey! They want to see you in the White House!" or whatever.
"Oh!" - that is happiness; it is not joy.
The world may have happiness – they find that in their environment and in their surroundings.
That is the world.
But joy is something only believers have.
Are you a believer?
I can't hear you.
(Yes!)
Are you a believer?
(Yes.)
You understand what I am saying.
That shows that joy is our conquering power.
Let someone say, “conquering power”.
(Conquering power.)
If you don’t have joy, no power - conquering power
Power to overcome sickness is joy.
Power to overcome hardship is joy.
Power to overcome isolation is joy.
Power to overcome affliction is joy.
If you don’t have joy, you cannot overcome this.
The Bible says, "All this will happen but cheer up, I have overcome."
(Amen.)
Conquering power.
Take note; whenever our joy seeps out and leaves us barren and empty,
it proves that we are out of fellowship, out of contact with God.
Anytime you notice that there is no joy - out of God.
You cannot pray - even when you are praying, you are not there.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Overflow Congregation
Whenever our joy seeps out,
it proves that we are out of fellowship, out of contact with God.
Whenever you find no joy - no fellowship, no joy - no contact with God.
I have joy - this is why you see me.
Say, "Joy is my conquering power".
Yes.
Conquering power.
When you have joy, you will overcome affliction.
You have affliction but you tell people, "With God all things are possible".
You will be laughing, you see people laughing and happy, whereas they have...
Look at Apostle Paul with a thorn in his flesh - go and read it in Corinthians.
The Bible did not tell us exactly the affliction he had, but we know it was an affliction from the pit of hell.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
As a Christian, trials may test you; they cannot destroy or rob your joy.
When you are not a believer, trials will destroy you,
will overthrow you from your position,
will take you out of God.
It is trial and affliction that cause all this today.
Many of us want to reestablish our relationship with God.
You keep going out, out, going out, out, going out because of trouble.
When you have trouble, you begin to say, "Why do I have this trouble?".
And you don't know that satan uses this to rob you of your joy,
to rob you of your relationship.
Temptation, affliction, poverty, hardship may test you as a man of faith;
they cannot destroy you because of joy.
(Amen.)
The SCOAN Sunday Service